出自第六季第四集
摩根发狂时常念叨的话
你知道是什么
You know what it is.
你本该知道的
You were supposed to.
不
No.
你本该知道的
You were supposed to!
不
No!
开始了
It's on.
这把枪能给我吗  等他们来时我好反击
Can I have that for when they come?
这不是你该做的事
This is not your lot.
你留在屋里  小亨利
You will stay inside, young Henry,
跟其他人待在一起  直到事情结束
with the others till it's done.
但我需要帮忙  我需要抵抗
But I need to help. I need to fight.
你不需要
No. You do not.
你需要待在屋里  保护这地方
You need to stay inside and guard this place.
你会活下去  并且帮别人活下去
You will live and help others do the same.
卡萝尔
Carol.
你知道我能帮忙的
You know I can help.
亨利  如果他们进攻时你在外面  你会死的
Henry, if you go out there during the attack, you'll die.
保护好他们
Protect them.
别放那里  放在角落
Not there. Those go in the corner.
你说你的特长是什么来着
What'd you say your specialty was?
美国医生头衔  指工作了两年的实习医生
我是第二年急诊住院医师
I was a second year EM resident at --
所以你从未做过手术
So you have never performed surgery.
做过三次
Three times.
截肢手术呢
Amputations?
没做过  但我会搞懂的
No, but I can figure it out.
你这力气能按住一个
Are you even strong enough to hold someone down
没被麻醉的人吗
who hasn't been anesthetized?
我会搞懂的
I can figure it out.
你能开枪吗
Can you shoot a gun?
更重要的是  你按住人的同时能开枪吗
More importantly, can you shoot a gun while you're holding someone down?
我很肯定我知道得够多...
I'm pretty sure I know enough to --
真的吗
Really?
因为在我听来  你任何事都懂得不够多
'Cause it sounds to me like you don't know enough of anything.
根据我的经验  一知半解的人
And in my experience, people who don't know enough
比完全不懂的人更危险
are more dangerous than people who don't know shit.
我知道有很多事我都没做过
There's a lot I haven't done, I know that,
但从我第一天去医院上班
but from my first day at the hospital
到这一刻为止
to this moment right now,
我做过的都是我没做过的事
all I've done are things I've never done.
现在有人要来袭击这里
There are people coming, right now, to hurt this place,
我站在这里  做好了帮忙的准备
and I'm standing here ready to help.
所以别问我做过什么
So stop asking me what I've done
而是告诉我该做什么
and start telling me what to do
除了把该死的毯子放在哪里
besides where to put the damn blankets.
我喜欢你
I like you.
做好准备
Get ready.
开始吧
Here we go.
《行尸走肉》
我还希望好好湿吻一番那扇门呢
Here I was hoping to give that gate a big ol' wet, sloppy kiss,
结果她却在玩欲擒故纵
and there she goes, playing hard to get.
阿拉特  加里
Arat, Gary,
把这些讨厌的东西从路上移开
remove these offending articles from the road.
太阳落山了
The sun is down.
我厌倦了等待
I'm tired of waiting.
尼根  我想跟尼根对话
Negan. I want to talk to Negan.
你好啊
Well, hello there.
你正在跟尼根对话
You are speaking to Negan,
但我的出生证明上写着"西蒙"
but my birth certificate says "Simon."
跟我进行这番不愉快对话的人是谁
With whom do I have the distinct displeasure of speaking?
玛姬
Maggie.
玛姬·李
Maggie Rhee.
寡妇
The Widow.
好吧
Well, then.
又见面了  李寡妇
Hello again, Widow Rhee,
请允许我致以哀悼
and allow me to offer my condolences.
针对过去发生的事和将要发生的事
For what's happened and what's about to happen.
为防我说得不够明白
In case it's not already plain as Hilltop potatoes,
在下谨代表尼根发言
yours truly is speaking on behalf of Negan this go 'round.
我向你保证老大本人
And I assure you that the man himself
亲自签收了你隔夜送达的包裹
personally received your care package next day delivery.
我注意到那个棺材
I noticed it was the box
就是我出于好意给你的那个
that I gave you in good faith --
我被骗了
trick's on me.
但是时候还债了
But the bill's come due,
你和你的人将付出代价
and you and your people are gonna have to pay.
恐怕是很严重的代价
Quite dearly, I'm afraid.
38个你的人还活着
Your 38 people are alive and breathing.
转身离开  别惹我们
Turn around and leave us be,
我们就留他们一命
and they stay that way.
如果你们不走  我会把38颗子弹
But if you don't, I have 38 bullets
亲自打到那38个人身上
that I will personally fire into all 38.
美好的夜晚不该浪费在慢慢死亡上
It's too nice a night to spend it dyin' slow,
你不觉得吗  西蒙
don't you think, Simon?
怎么说
How's this gonna go?
玛姬·李
Well, Maggie Rhee,
这真是太令人遗憾了  但在我看来
this is highly regrettable, but the way I see it,
你抓住的那些救世军
the Saviors you're in possession of there
都是残损品
are damaged goods.
他们自己陷入了困境
You know, they've got themselves into their own pickle,
而本组织只奖励那些
and this organization prizes those who,
A  没被抓住的人
"A," avoid capture
以及  B  出事之后自己想办法的人
and, "B," ‭figure out their own shit when said outcome eventuates.
总而言之  我的意思是  去他们的
Which, in the end, ‭is my way of saying screw them.
你真觉得如此荒谬的办法能起作用吗
Did you really think that cockamamie play would work?
会起作用的
It will.
好了  大伙儿们
Alright, people.
开始狂欢吧
Let's get this party started.
尽管我们没带什么枪炮来
And though we do not come bearing munitions,
记住了  计划有变
remember -- the plan has changed.
我们的目标不再是感染他们  而是杀死他们
Our goal is not merely infection -- it is conclusion.
我们要把这些人都干掉
We are doing away with these people.
全部干掉
All of 'em.
这不是他想要的
This isn't what he'd want.
你心里清楚  对吧
You know that, right?
他可能还活着
He could still be out there.
你确定等他回来之后你想面对这个吗
You sure you wanna face that with him if he shows?
乞求宽恕总比请求允许要好  小德
Better to beg forgiveness than ask permission, D.
以后的问题以后再说
Future problems.
上  趁这些混蛋没关门先冲进去
Go! Through the gate before the assholes close it!
动手
Now!
后面的  干掉他们
Boys in back, light 'em up!
把人质带到我办公室  在结束前看好他们
Take the prisoners to my office. Hold 'em there 'til it's done.
走吧  快  进去  快进去
Let's go. Go. Inside! Get inside!
我可以帮你保卫这个地方
I can help you defend this place.
我想帮忙
I want to.
拜托了  玛姬
Please, Maggie.
你觉得我有理由忠于那些人吗
You think I got a reason to be loyal to these people?
玛姬  你进来吗
Maggie -- you coming?
他到底在哪
Where the hell is he?
瞭望台  撤退  前线  掩护他们
Lookouts, fall back! Front line, give 'em cover!
好久不见
Long time, no see.
没事的  有我呢
It's okay. I'm here.
我来解决转角那个小可爱
I'll take out sunshine around the corner.
-除非你想搞定她  小德  -不想
- Unless you want her, D. - ‭No.
那下一个你来搞定怎么样
Well, how 'bout the next one, then?
我现在需要团队合作
I'm gonna need a group effort here.
快走
Go.
我守着他
I'll stay with him.
塔拉
Tara!
达里尔  时候到了
Daryl, it's time.
玛姬发信号了  我们得走了
Maggie gave the signal. We gotta go.
达里尔
Daryl!
屁都看不清
I can't see shit.
这些人以前就逃跑过
These people have run before.
阿拉特  带几个人绕后
Arat, take a team around back.
包围这个地方
I want the place surrounded.
加里  你的小队去拖车那边
Gary, your group goes for the trailers.
-慢点  轻点  明白吗  -明白
- Slow and quiet, capiche? - Yeah.
剩下的人呢
The rest of us?
剩下的人搞个上门服务
The rest of us are making a house call.
如果家里有人的话
Well, if anybody's home...
该适当屠宰一下了
it's time to do ‭some proper slaughtering.
妈的  不要
God damn it, no!
退到卡车那边去  快快快
Back to the trucks! Go! Go! Go!
走  走
Move! Move!
继续走
Keep moving!
别起来
Just stay down.
你知道是什么
You know what it is.
You know what it is!
我想杀了他们
I wanted them dead.
杀光他们
All of them.
尤其是尼根
Negan most of all.
是啊
Yeah.
我也是
Me too.
你看到他了吗
Did you see him?
他没来
He wasn't here.
我在外边看到过他
I saw him out there.
我离队想杀了他
I broke away and tried to kill him.
没得手  但我努力过
I didn't, but I tried.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们没资源击退下一次进攻了
We don't have the resources to fight off another attack.
准备撤离吧
Be ready to go.
你不该出来的
Hey. ‭You shouldn't be out here.
只是擦伤而已
Oh, it's just...it's just a scratch.
我能帮忙
I can help.
万一伤更重怎么办
What if it wasn't?
那就是我自己的错了
Then it'd be my own damn fault.
因为我  他才回救世军的
He's back with them because of me.
不  他回救世军是因为他就是那种人
No, he's back with 'em 'cause that's who he is.
我们很幸运
We...We got lucky.
碰到了玛姬  瑞克
Finding Maggie...Rick.
本可能不一样的
It could've been different.
以前我跟着总督时就不一样
It was, for me, ‭when I was with the Governor.
是的  但现在你不跟总督了
Yeah, but you weren't one of 'em.
可我以前跟过
But I was with them.
你哥哥也跟过
Your brother, too.
我哥
My brother?
我哥一生都没走对路
My brother ran the wrong way his whole life.
如果他还在  如果他走的时候我跟着他
If he were here, if I stuck with him when he left,
我们也会加入救世军
we'd be with the Saviors, too,
或加入其他一样坏的团体
or some other group just like 'em.
但我会看清他们的真面目  就像你一样
But I'd have figured out who they were just like you did.
也许德怀特也是这样
Maybe that's what happened to Dwight.
那是在他杀死你女朋友之前还是之后
Is that before or after he killed your girl?
还是说你们已经两清了
Or is that all square now?
两清了
It is.
我可能会永远恨他  但他救了我的命
Look, I might hate him forever, but he saved my life.
不  他昨晚想杀了你
No, he tried to kill you last night.
我们在树林时  在来这的路上
When we were in the woods, when we were coming here,
我看到他尽力帮我们赢
I saw him try and help us win.
嗯  我也看到了我看到的
Yeah. I saw what I saw, too.
给你留了块萝卜
Saved you this turnip.
我不吃
Yeah. I'm okay.
瑞克
Rick...
玛姬为了省油把发电机关了
Maggie turned off the generators to save on gas.
这么热的天  孩子们需要新鲜空气
The kids are gonna need air in this heat.
能让我看看你的伤口吗
Can I take a look at that cut?
我有清洗的用品
I have some stuff to clean it.
让我先把这个干完
Let me get this done first.
我看到他在车队后面
I saw him at the back of the convoy.
所以我才那么做
That's why I did it.
我必须试一下
I had to try.
必须
I had to.
我们可以让你出去  派个守卫跟着你
We can get you outside the gates...with a guard.
让你埋葬你的人
So you can bury your people.
他们不是我的人
They're not mine.
但我很欣慰你这样看待他们
But I'm glad you see them that way.
当人看
As people.
怎么了
What is it?
只是...  你是个好领袖
Just...you're a good leader.
我之前就知道  但昨晚
I knew it before, but last night...
你保住了大门
You saved the gates.
你救了整个社区
You saved the community.
你救了很多人命
You saved lives.
因为他们牺牲了自己的命
Because they sacrificed theirs.
我救囚犯  仅是因为尼根还在
I only saved the prisoners 'cause Negan is still in play.
所以他们还有利用价值
Which means they could be.
我用棺材给尼根寄去那具尸体是为了激怒他
I sent Negan that body in the box to make him mad.
引他来这
To lure him here.
因为我希望我丈夫的坟
'Cause I wanted my husband's...grave
是他最后看见的东西
to be the last thing he saw.
即使要付出代价
Even if it came at a cost.
我不知道这样的我是不是好领袖
I don't know if that makes me a good leader.
我只知道我唯一的遗憾是
I do know ‭that the only regret I have
尼根不在那堆尸体中
is that Negan is not in that pile of bodies.
你让我很担心
You had me worried.
这个嘛
Well...
如果我知道被刺一刀能得到你的关注
if I'd known getting stabbed would get your attention,
我早就这么做了
I would've done it a lot sooner.
抱歉我那样离开
I'm sorry for how I left.
我对你所做的事
What I did to you.
我不需要你的道歉
I don't need an apology.
你不欠我什么
You don't owe me anything.
不过  我的确一直在思考原因
But, uh, I guess I have been wondering why.
你对我动过真感情吗
Was any of it real?
我当时不想要真感情
I didn't want it to be real.
我只是在演戏
I was pretending.
不用顾及我的感受
Well, don't go easy on me here.
我当时想好好生活
I was trying to live a life.
之后发现我们还没消灭救世军
Then we found out that we hadn't gotten rid of the Saviors.
会有更多的斗争和死亡
And that there would be more fighting and more dying.
我受不了
And I couldn't.
当时正好...
And it was right about the time that...
感觉...
it felt like --
感觉好像是...
like -- like maybe it wasn't...
好像不用再装下去了
like maybe it wasn't going to be pretending anymore.
也许
Maybe.
好吧
Well...
这可能是其他人给我说过的
that just might be one of the nicest things
最好的话之一了
anybody's ever said to me.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你还会离开吗
You gonna leave again?
在一切结束之后
After it's over?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想我可能只是接受了
I think I might just accept that
有些人足够幸运可以活下来
some of us are lucky enough to just live,
有些人足够幸运可以去战斗
some of us are ‭lucky enough to just fight.
结束之后也是吗
Even after it ends?
我不认为会结束
I don't think it ends.
我们在做的事
What we're doing...
这场战争的结束  是我们战斗的目标
The end of the fight is -- is what we're fighting for.
获胜只代表我们赢了明天
Winning just means we get tomorrow.
也许再加一晚
Maybe one more night.
也许再加一个早晨
Maybe one more morning.
在那之后
After that...
无法保证
no guarantees.
我出去参战也不会死的
I wouldn't have died if I went out there.
你会的  亨利
You would have, Henry.
相信我  你会的
Just trust me -- you would have.
我可以帮你处理伤口
I could treat your wound.
不要感染了
Wouldn't want it to get infected.
有一种为亡者祈祷的仪式
There's, um... a prayer for the dead
我第一次听到的时候还是个小孩
I first heard when I was a little boy.
最后一句是
It, uh... ended with the phrase,
不要让我们跟随他们误入歧途
"Do not send us astray after 'them'" --
-那些死去的人  -别说了
- those who died... - ‭Don't.
感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
我还好
I'm okay.
西迪克和丹娜医生很棒
Siddiq and Dr. Dana, they're -- they're good.
缝合的时候都没感觉到
Didn't even feel 'em stitching me up.
有他们在  我们很幸运
We're lucky to have 'em.
有你在  我们很幸运
We're lucky to have you.
如果是格雷戈里掌事
If Gregory was in charge,
这个地方会不复存在
this -- this place wouldn't be here anymore.
他只顾自己
He was about himself.
只管自己想要什么
What he wanted.
你不是这样的
That's not you.
怎么了
Hey. What's going on?
不是...  他们...
Mnh...it wasn't...they...
你发烧了
Ah, you're burning up.
我去叫医生
I'm gonna go get the doctor.
坚持住
Just hold tight.
你是格雷戈里吗
You're Gregory, right?
谢天谢地
Thank God.
我是
Yes.
放我出去
Let me out.
你知道是谁杀了我哥哥吗
Do you know which one killed my brother?
我不知道你哥哥是谁
I-I don't know who your brother is.
这些人我一个都不认识
I-I don't know any of these people.
我和他们不是一伙的
I'm not one of them.
你拿的武器非常危险  孩子
That's a very dangerous weapon you got there, kiddo.
我不希望你受伤
Uh, I don't want you to get hurt --
我不希望任何人受伤
I don't want anyone to get hurt.
你何不交给我  然后我们谈谈
Why don't you give it to me, and we can talk, huh?
你哥哥的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about your brother.
杀死他们不会让他起死回生
Killing them ‭isn't gonna bring him back.
没错
No.
但那会令我好受些
But it'll make me feel better.
已经好受过一次了
It already did once.
如果你和他们不是一伙  为什么会被关进去
And why would you be in here if you're not with them?
我又不傻
I'm not dumb.
你们某人知道谁杀了本
One of you knows who killed Ben,
如果有必要的话  我会一个个枪杀你们
and if I have to, ‭I'm gonna start shooting people
直到某人告诉我
until someone tells me.
孩子  我懂
Hey, kid. I get it.
我哥哥也死了
My -- My big brother died, too.
杀一些或许与你哥哥的死有关的人
Killing a buncha guys who mighta had something to do with it
虽然听起来很爽
sounds pretty damn good in theory.
但是  那不会让你好受
But, uh, it's not gonna make you feel any better.
不会维持很久
Not for long.
我知道的
I know.
-怎么了  艾尔  -没什么  继续睡
- What's up, Al? - Nothing. Go back to sleep.
以西结  掩护我们背后
Ezekiel, please watch our back.
瑞克  我需要你...
Rick, ‭I'm gonna need you to...
好的
Yeah.
快来
Come on.
如音乐般动听
Music to my ears.
是你吗
Was it you?
我不知道你在说什么  孩子
I don't know what the hell you're talking about, kid.
我想知道谁杀了我哥哥
I want the guy who killed my brother.
谁最好现在就告诉我
Somebody better tell me now!
我知道你很愤怒  好吗  我当时也是
Look, I know you're angry. Okay? I know. I was, too.
但是真做出来比嘴上说说更难挽回
But words are a lot easier t-to live with than actions, all right?
男人一点  站出来
Be a man and step forward
这样我就不用杀你的朋友们了
so I don't have to kill your friends.
我会数到十  然后开始射击
I'm gonna count to 10 and start shooting.
一  二  三
1...2...3...
四  五
...4...5...
门开了  弟兄们  快跑
Gate's open, boys! Let's go!
发生了什么
The hell happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许行尸进来了
Maybe walkers got in.
也许是战斗时混进来的
Maybe during the fight.
但他们都是我们自己人
These are our own people, though.
退后
Stay back!
你没事吗
You alright?
没事  只是...
Yeah, just...
他没被咬
He wasn't bit.
但他转变了
But he turned.
尼根的球棒
Negan's bat.
我和他在外面时  球棒沾满了尸血
When I was out there with him, it was covered in walker blood.
我以为他只是碰到了一些行尸
I just thought he'd crossed some.
但是或许
But maybe...
他们又奴役我们了
They have us working for them again.
让我们自相残杀
Killin' our own.
是发烧
It's the fever.
就是这个
That's what it is.
现在说得通了
It makes sense now.
你们某人
One of you...
必须动手
you're gonna have to do it.
我做不到
I can't.
你必须替我做
You gotta do it for me.
求你了
Please.
外面还好吗
Good out there?
房子安全了
House is clear.
怎么回事
How'd this happen?
救世军对武器做了一些处理
Um...the Saviors did something to their weapons.
任何被他们割伤或击中的人
Everyone they cut up... or got shot...
都会生病
they all got sick.
其中一些人转变了
Some of 'em turned.
什么
What?
不
No.
好的
Okay.
我们在外面时
When we were out there,
你说你等够了
and you said you were done waiting,
我本能杀了他的
I coulda killed him.
我应该杀了他的
I shoulda.
不  他想和我们在一起
No. He wanted to be here with us.
不管他怎么做  不管他怎么努力
And no matter what he did or how hard he tried,
我都希望他死
I wanted him dead.
我无法接受其他结果
I just couldn't ‭let it be anything else.
命运弄人  对吧
Karma's a bitch, right?
举起手来
Hands up, now!
我们是在帮忙
Hey, we're trying to help!
一个孩子来打开了围栏  里面有人转变了
A-A-A kid came and opened up the pen. We had people turn.
一部分人逃了
A bunch of 'em left, but a
但也有一部分人在试图关上门
bunch of 'em are trying to close that gate.
玛姬  看
Maggie, look.
戴安
Dianne.
得令  走
We're on it. Come on.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing out here?
我想来看看囚犯  但围栏空了
I went to check on the prisoners, but the pen was empty.
其他人呢
Where are the others?
他们没说去哪
They didn't say where they were goin'.
他们只是跑了
They just ran.
你没跑吗
And you didn't?
你看到了我们对尼根和西蒙来说一文不值
You saw what we mean to Negan and Simon.
说这话可能很蠢
Which might be a dumb thing to say --
我们对你们来说也不值什么
it doesn't make us worth much to your people, either,
但是留下的人都是真心的
but...those of us that stayed, stayed.
我们有很多机会逃跑
We had plenty of chances to run.
亨利
Henry!
亨利  如果你在下面  快出来
Henry, if you're down here, come on out!
我们所有地方都找过了
Yo. ‭We've checked everywhere.
孩子不见了
The little man's gone.
有几个救世军说在其他人逃跑前
Hey. Some of the Saviors said Henry broke into the pen,
亨利闯进了围栏里
just before the others escaped.
他之前在那里  现在不在了
He was down there, and then he wasn't.
我告诉过他会发生什么
I told him... ‭I told him what would happen.
你知道是什么
You know what it is.
You know what it is!
你知道是什么
You know what it is.
你知道是什么  你知道的
You know what it is! You know!
怎么了
What is it?
代价太大
The cost.